So the next units will be concerned with probabilities.
所以接下来的单元是关于概率
Particularly with restructured probabilities using Bayes Networks.
尤其是使用贝叶斯网络重构概率
This is some of the most involved material in this class.
这是这节课最常用的材料
And, since this is a Stanford level class,
另外由于这是斯坦福级别的课程
you'll find out that some of the quizzes are actually really hard.
你会发现一些测验实际上很难
So, as you go through the material,
所以当你浏览材料时
I hope the hardness of the quizzes won't discourage you.
希望测验的难度并没有让你灰心丧气
It'll really entice you to take a piece of paper and a pen and work them out.
这的确可以让你拿起纸和笔解决问题
Let me give you a flavor of a Bayes Network, using an example.
我先来用一个例子解释下贝叶斯网络
Suppose you find in the morning that your car won't start.
假设早上你发现汽车无法启动
Well, there's many causes why your car might not start.
可能有许多原因导致汽车无法启动
One is that your battery is flat.
首先可能是电池没电了
Even for a flat battery, there's multiple causes.
除了电池没电 还会有各种原因
One, it's just plain dead.
也可能只是没电了
And one is that the battery is okay, but it's not charging.
如果电池没问题 可能是没有充电
The reason why a battery might not charge is that the alternator
电池无法充电的原因可能是
may be broken.
发电机坏了
Or the fan belt might be broken.
或者风扇传送皮带坏了
If you look at this influence diagram, also called a Bayes network,
如果你观察这个影响图 即贝叶斯网络
you'll find there's many different ways to explain that the car won't start.
你会发现解释汽车无法启动的各种不同原因
And a natural question you might have is, can we diagnose the problem?
你可能自然而然地问到 我们可以诊断问题吗？
One diagnostic tool is a battery meter.
诊断工具之一是电池安时计
Which may increase or
可以增加或
decrease your belief that the battery may cause your car failure.
减少你对电池引发汽车失灵的信度
You might also know your battery age.
你也可以了解电池寿命
Older batteries tend to go dead more often.
老旧电池经常坏掉
And there's many other ways to look at reasons why the car might not start.
还有其他方式可以查看汽车无法启动的原因
You might inspect the lights, the oil light, the gas gauge.
你可以检查车灯 油量灯 汽油表
You might even dip into the engine to see what the oil level is with
甚至可以查看发动机
a dipstick.
使用量油尺检查油面水平
And all of those relate to alternative reasons to why the car might not be
这些都是与汽车无法启动的
starting.
其他相关原因
Like no oil, no gas, the fuel line might be blocked, or
例如没有油和气 供油管受到堵塞
the starter may be broken.
或者启动器坏了
And all of these can influence your measurements, like the oil light or
这些都会以各种方式影响你的测量 如油量灯
the gas gauge, in different ways.
汽油表
For example, the battery flat would have an effect on the lights,
例如电池没电会影响车灯
it might in fact have an effect on the oil light and on the gas gauge.
实际上会影响油量灯和汽油表
But it won't really affect the oil you measure with the dipstick,
不过并不会影响你使用量油尺 测量油量
that is affected by the actual oil level, which also affects the oil light.
这受到实际油量水平的影响 油量水平也会影响油量灯
Gas will affect the gas gauge.
燃气会影响汽油表
And of course, without gas the car doesn't start.
当然没有燃气 汽车也没法启动
So this is a complicated structure that really describes one
这是个复杂的结构 真正描述了
way to understand how a car doesn't start.
理解汽车无法启动的一种原因
A car is a complex system,
汽车是个复杂的系统
there's lots of variables you can't really measure immediately.
存在许多变量 你无法理解真正测量出来
And it has sensors,
并且它还有些传感器
which allow you to understand a little bit about the state of the car.
可以让你理解一些汽车的状态
What the Bayes Network does, it really assists you in reasoning from
贝叶斯网络的作用在于真正帮助你
observable variables like the car won't start and the value of the dip stick,
根据可观测变量 例如汽车无法启动和量油尺的值
to hidden causes like is the fan belt broken or is the battery dead?
推断出潜在原因 如风扇传送皮带坏掉或电池没电
What you have here is a Bayes Network.
这里你得到贝叶斯网络
A Bayes Network is composed of nodes,
贝叶斯网络由节点组成
these nodes correspond to events that you might or might not know.
这些节点对应你可能了解和不了解的事件
They're typically called random variables.
它们一般称为随机变量
These nodes are linked by arcs, and the arcs suggest
这些节点由弧线连接 这些弧线表明
that a child of an arc is influenced by its parent.
弧线的子节点受到双亲的影响
But not in a deterministic way, it might be influenced in a probabilistic way.
但不是以确定性方式 而是以概率方式受到影响
Which means in order a battery, for example,
例如这意味着电池问题
has a higher chance of causing the battery to be dead.
引起电池没电的可能性更大
But it's not clear that every old battery is dead.
但是并不清楚每个老旧电池都没电
There's a total of 16 variables in this Bayes Network.
在这个贝叶斯网络中 总共有 16 个变量
What the graph structure and associated probabilities specify is
图形结构和相关概率说明
a huge probability distribution in the space of all of these 16 variables.
在所有这些 16 个变量的空间中具有极大的概率分布
If they are binary, which we will assume throughout this unit,
如果它们是二元的 我们在整个单元都可以假设是二元关系
they can take 2 to the 16 different values, which is a lot.
可以得到 2 到 16 个不同值 非常多
The Bayes Network, as we find out,
正如我们看到的 贝叶斯网络
is a complex representation of a distribution over this very
是对分布的复杂表现形式
very large joint probability distribution of all these variables.
针对所有变量的大型联合概率分布
Further, once we specify the Bayes Network,
另外我们一旦指定贝叶斯网路
we can observe for example, the car won't start.
例如我们观察汽车无法启动的贝叶斯网络
You can observe things like the oil light, and the lights, and
你会发现一些事情 如量油灯 车灯
the battery meter.
和电池安时计
And then compute probabilities of hypothesis like the alternator is
然后计算假设概率 如发电机坏掉
broken, or the fan belt is broken, or the battery is dead.
风扇传送皮带坏掉 电池没电
So in this class, you're going to talk about how to construct this
所以这节课中你将会探讨如何构建这个
Bayes Network, what the semantics are.
贝叶斯网络 语义是什么
And how to reason in this Bayes Network to find out about variables you
怎样通过这个贝叶斯网络推断发现你无法观察到的变量
can't observe, like whether the fan belt is broken or not.
如风扇传送皮带是否坏掉
That's an overview.
这是个概览
Throughout this unit, I'm going to assume that every event is discrete,
在整个单元中 我将会假设每个事件是独立的
expect it's binary.
除了二元关系
We'll start with some consideration of basic probability.
我们首先考虑基本概率
We work our way into some simple Bayes Networks.
讨论一些简单的贝叶斯网络
We'll talk about concepts like conditional independence.
我们讨论条件独立性等概念
And then, define Bayes Networks more generally.
然后从更广泛的角度定义贝叶斯网络
Move into concepts like D-separation and start doing parameter counts.
然后转向分隔定理 进行参数计算
Later on, Peter will tell you about inference of Bayes Networks, so
之后 Peter 会告诉你贝叶斯网络的推论
we won't do this in this class.
我们这节课不涉及这个内容
I can't over emphasize how important this class is.
我不会过分强调这节课的重要性
Bayes Networks are used extensively in almost all fields of
贝叶斯网络广泛应用于
smart computer systems, in diagnostics, for prediction, for
智能计算机系统的所有领域 包括诊断 预测
machine learning, in a field like finance, inside Google, in robotics.
机器学习 金融 谷歌和机器人学
Bayes Networks are also the building blocks of more advanced AI techniques,
贝叶斯网络也是更多高级人工智能技巧的基础
such as particle filters, hidden Markov models, MDP's and
如粒子滤波 隐马尔可夫模型 数据处理模块化工具包 (MDP‘s)
POMDP's, Kalman filters, and many others.
不完全可观察马尔可夫决策过程 (POMDP) 卡尔曼滤波等等
These are words that don't sound familiar quite yet, but as you go
这些词语可能听起来非常陌生
through the class, I can promise you you will get to know what they mean.
但是学完本节后 我保证你会理解这些词的含义
So let's start now at the very, very basics.
那么我们首先从最最基础的内容开始